# JOSH KILGORE JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

615.473.0190

kilgore.josh@gmail.com

joshkilgore.com

# PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Full-Stack Web Development

jQuery

JavaScript

AngularJS GitHub

Oitiiub

HTML

C#

.NET Framework

MVC/Razor

**Test-Driven Development** 

Git

Licensed Attorney

# **SOCIAL MEDIA**



https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-kilgore-esg-6946b924/



@jkillz2020



@younglawTN

# **EDUCATION**

**JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER** 

Nashville Software School | 2016 - 2017

JURIS DOCTORATE

Nashville School of Law | 2008 - 2012

# **ABOUT ME**

I am a licensed attorney turned coder. I have always been a lover of technology and want to use my newly minted skills in software development to solve new challenges and add immediate value to a company with my professional experience and coding skills.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### APPRENTICE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | Jan 2016 - Jun 2017

- Intensive full-time software development bootcamp focusing on C#/.Net development fundamentals and problem solving. The final three months of the program being executed in a simulated company environment with SCRUM methodology.
- Daily hands on application of OOP fundamentals through group and individual projects
- Created single page applications in JavaScript in the Angular framework as well as HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and Materialize
- Worked with jQuery for JavaScript libraries
- Leveraged Razor for creating and editing MVC applications
- Deployed applications through Firebase
- Source code/version control with Git/GitHub
- Project management/tracking with Trello and GitHub Issue Tracking
- Solution Design: whiteboarding and wireframes
- Created RESTful API's with MVC.Net and Web API
- Retrieved and stored database information in Firebase, and SQL;
- Testing with Mog
- Utilized Gulp to automate bundling of modules, JavaScript linting, and compiling Sass
- Leveraged VMware for partitioning Mac and Windows environments to utilize Visual Studio 2015 IDE
- · Code reviews in Github of peers' code

#### **ATTORNEY**

State of Tennessee, Dept. of Commerce and Insurance, Special Counsel, Counsel On Call | Jan 2013 - Present

 Utilized different software platforms such as Relativity, Catalyst and Axcelerate along with SharePoint to review large e-discovery document requests

## **PROJECTS**

#### STOKED!

Front-End Capstone | Dec 2016

Deployed here: capstone-stoked.firebaseapp.com

Utilized Angular to build a CRUD app that allows user to login, search Google Places API to search for and save a ski resort to their profile using Firebase backend and get a 4-day weather report via a weather API call.

Users can save and rate their favorite runs which correlate to each resort.

#### COMIC COLLECTION APP

Back-End Capstone | Jun 2017

In-Development

Using C# with the ASP.NET WebAPI to build a back-end connected to Angular front-end that allows user to login, call Marvel Comics API and obtain/save data about their comic book collection.